PATRICK J. DALTON

WEB DEVELOPMENT & DESIGN

DETAILS

PHONE

773.512.7765

EMAIL

patrickjdalton1@gmail.com

SKILLS

HTML5/CSS3

• • • • •

JavaScript (Fullstack: React, Node.js, Express)

• • • •

PHP (Drupal, CakePHP)

• • • •

SQL (MySQL, T-SQL, SSRS)

• • • •

Testing Frameworks (Jest, Mocha)

• • • • 0

Prototyping

• • • •

NoSQL (Mongo)

• • • • 0

Templating Engines (Mustache, Handlebars, EJS, Jade)

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$

Git

• • • •

Troubleshooting / Debugging

• • • • •

Bash scripting

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

JIRA / ZenDesk

• • • • •

Microsoft IIS

• • • 0 0

C# .NET

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

ColdFusion

• • • • •

PROFILE

My varied experiences over the last 10+ years in Chicago I.T. have equipped me with a versatile toolkit, which I leverage when tackling new problems or acquiring new skills. I am humble, service-minded and constantly striving to expand my knowledge and experiences.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Application Support Analyst, American Hospital Association

Chicago, IL

Jan 2019

- · Writing/maintaining complex T-SQL stored procedures/functions
- · API development and design
- Building/maintaining functionality of AHA's storefront and all proximal systems
- · Leading projects in the role of project manager/technical lead
- · Authoring and maintaining detailed database and API documentation
- · Participating in change control processes
- · Providing advanced tier-4 support to end-users

Web Developer, BPOE USA

Chicago, IL

Sep 2015 — Jan 2019

- Building and maintaining large-scale applications for membership management (PHP, ColdFusion)
- · Refactoring and modernizing old code
- · User interface design and front-end development
- · Developing wireframes / prototypes for new website functionality
- · Supporting BPOE systems and users at all support tiers
- · Print / email design

Web Engineer, National Association of Realtors

Chicago, IL

Jun 2014 — Sep 2015

- Leading / supporting projects by translating requirements into functional mobile-first web systems
- · Regular presentations to upper management
- · LAMP development (Drupal)
- · UI prototyping (Balsamiq) and design (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JS, jQuery)

Director, Technical Support, NeonCRM

Chicago, IL

Jun 2009 — Dec 2013

- Building utilities for analyzing internal performance, peak submission times, resolution cycles
- \cdot Deep usage of issue resolution and tracking software (ZenDesk, JIRA)
- · Extensive technical consulting and client management
- · Developing customer retention strategies

XSL

REST/SOAP

Postman

• • • • •

- Proposing new approaches to problems based on data-driven insights and discoveries
- · Managing a team of support agents

EDUCATION

Fullstack Software Development, Northwestern University

Chicago, IL

Sep 2020 — Mar 2021

Computer Science, Concordia University

River Forest, IL

Aug 2006 — Aug 2009